Adriana Niño

Full Stack Developer

Austin, TX 737.328	6 <u>ninadri.dev@gmail.com</u>	<u>LinkedIn</u> <u>GitH</u>	Iub ninadri.com
--------------------	--------------------------------	-----------------------------	-------------------

I'm a seasoned customer service expert on a journey to become a coding aficionado! I'm an artist at heart and being able to incorporate that into the tech world has been most exciting for me. Though I'm new to coding, the Full Stack Development Bootcamp at the University of Texas at Austin has shown me endless possibilities, and I hope to explore them with your company.

EDUCATION

The Coding Boot Camp - University of Texas at Austin

Austin Web Development Boot Camp
Rigorous 24-week full stack development course.

Austin, TX Feb 2024- Aug 2024

Udemy

The Ultimate React Course 2024: React, Next.js, Redux & More The Complete JavaScript Course 2024: From Zero to Expert!

Online Ongoing

SKILLS

Frontend: HTML5, CSS, jQuery, JavaScript, React, Bootstrap, The DOM, APIs, JSON, AJAX

Backend: SQL, MongoDB, Express, ReactJS, Node, NoSQL, Testing

Soft Skills: Resourceful, Creative, Leadership, Problem Solving, Adaptable, Organization, Motivated

PROJECTS

Weather Search | Front-End | Repo | Deployed

Developed a user-friendly weather dashboard using **HTML**, **CSS**, **JavaScript**, and **Server-Side APIs** to display current and 5-day weather forecasts for cities worldwide. Implemented a feature that saves the last searched cities as buttons for quick access and reference.

My Blog | Front-End | Repo | Deployed

A platform enabling users to effortlessly craft blog posts, providing them the flexibility to either preserve or discard their creations at their discretion. Developed a content form with **HTML**, **CSS**, **Web APIs**, and **JavaScript** that renders a dynamic blog post and integrated a light/dark mode toggle for enhanced user experience

Travel List | Front-End | <u>Repo</u> | <u>Deployed</u>

Developed a travel packing list app with **React** that allows users to add items with quantities, track packing progress, sort items by multiple criteria, and clear the items once packing is complete.

E-Commerce Back End | Back-End | *Repo*

Developed a back-end system for an e-commerce website using **Express.js**, **PostgreSQL**, and **Sequelize**, enabling a manager to create, seed, and manage the database, start the server, and perform **CRUD** operations through **API routes**.

Employee Tracker System | Back-End | *Repo*

Developed a command-line application for business owners to view and manage departments, roles, and employees, enabling better organization and planning. Built using **SQL**, the application allows managers to add employees, assign them to managers, update their departments and roles, set salaries, and view all information in a table.

EXPERIENCE

Business Associate

Heartland Dental - Leander, TX - August 2023 - Current

Greet and welcome patients, managing front office duties including phone calls, emails, and mail. Utilized Dentrix for scheduling, patient records, and filing insurance claims. Verified benefits, explained coverage, posted payments, and processed accounts receivables. Reviewed treatment plan fees and payment options with patients.

Healthy Living Lead

H-E-B – Lakeway, TX – January 2021– August 2023

Supervise and train department employees to meet performance standards, plan engaging displays to enhance the customer experience, and foster strong customer relationships by understanding their health goals. Collaborate with other departments, analyze sales data to forecast future projects, and develop innovative ideas to improve team and department performance.

Healthy Living Representative

H-E-B – *Lakeway, TX* – *June 2019* – *December 2020*

Received "Partner of The Week" for exceptional performance shortly after joining, contributing to the success of both the previous and new departments. Created personalized experiences by interacting with customers. Conducted daily inventory inspections to inform ordering forecasts. Coordinated with management to stay updated on daily changes and ensure seamless operations.

Curbside

H-E-B - Austin, TX - Jan 2019 - June 2019

Fulfilled customers' online orders by coordinating with specialized departments to obtain specific products. Reviewed customer notes to update any changes and made outbound calls to inform members. Conducted daily audits of completed orders to identify and resolve any discrepancies.

Order Fulfilment

WHOOP - Remote - Mar 2022 - May 2022

Provided members with information on orders and returns, updated personal details, and processed refunds. Participated in daily team meetings to brainstorm improvements and communicated with fulfillers for order approvals. Utilized Zendesk, Shopify, and Salesforce.com to enhance efficiency and service quality.

Member Service Representative

WHOOP – Remote – Mar 2022 – May 2022

Achieved promotion to **Order Fulfilment** within three months by consistently exceeding departmental metrics and KPIs. Utilized technical skills in Zendesk and Salesforce.com to facilitate onboarding product demos, providing tailored troubleshooting assistance via phone and email. Efficiently escalated support tickets with detailed information, ensuring swift resolutions and earning multiple 5-star reviews for exceptional personalized support.